# **JEFFREY XUE**

#### SUMMARY

Jeffrey is a full-stack developer who has ten years of experience working in a variety of technologies for clients such as React, AngularJS, Vue, Node.js, and PHP. He has a Bachelor's and Master's degree in Computer Science and a strong portfolio of work to demonstrate his skills. He prides himself on his extreme attention to detail, efficiency, and delivering high-value work.

As a software developer with over 10 years of experience, he is comfortable with a myriad of tools and libraries (React 16, Redux, Redux-saga, Vue.js/Vuex, TypeScript) and more than proficient with accessible HTML5, responsive CSS, and JavaScript on both the front and back end.

He's also handy with Node.js, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Express, Sass, and whatever else is needed to spin up a development environment, run tests, or deploy components.

## **EDUCATION**

### The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

Apr 2010 - Oct 2012, Hong Kong

#### Master of Computer Science

- Software Engineering
- Cyber Security

## The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

Apr 2004 - Oct 2008, Hong Kong

#### Bachelor of Computer Science

- Computer Science
- Software Engineering
- 00P(Object-oriented programming) languages
- Cyber Security

#### SKILLS

Web Programming: React, Vue, Angular, Node, TypeScript, Javascript, PHP, Laravel

Mobile Programming: React Native, Xamarins, Swift

eCommerce: WordPress, Shopify, Shopify Plus

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon DynamoDB

APIs: Social Media, Google APIs, Web API/JSON/SOAP, OAuth

Testing: Unit Testing, E2E Testing

Platforms: Linux, MacOS, Windows, Docker

Tools: Git, IDE, Amazon Web Service

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Quantum Mob, Toronto, Canada - Principle Full Stack Developer

May 2018 - March 2021

- Oversaw the development of a real-time web app for one of the biggest mobile games companies in Toronto. The app lets administrators control the flow of a live session of one of their multiplayer games using a set of third-party APIs and the MQTT protocol. Each user had the capability of creating and customizing their own dashboards using a set of different widgets.
- Served as the team/tech lead of the team responsible for building several new websites for AirMiles, a well-known customer loyalty program in Canada.
- Set up AirMiles' project scaffolding, analyzed requirements, created user stories, performed code reviews, and coded among other tasks. These websites have a considerable amount of public traffic so performance and scalability were paramount.
- Mentored less experienced developers by defining and implementing a thorough code review process.

Technologies: Auth0, Contentful, Node.js, TypeScript, Next.js, React

## **Pragmars, Toronto, Canada** - Full Stack Developer

May 2015 - March 2018

- Developed a web solution to provide participants of the California Workers' Compensation system with litigated case data and documents (React.js with Apollo Client and Recompose).
- Built a GraphQL API that feeds the web app and also handles authentication.
- Thoroughly tested the back-end business logic using Jest.
- Ensured the durability of the front-end React.js component by testing it with Jest and Enzyme.

Technologies: GraphQL, React, Node.js

#### Starcom Madiavest Group, Hong Kong - Web Developer

February 2013 - March 2015

- Created a POC desktop app using ASP.NET WinForms, LINQ, and MDX queries.
  The app, using a statistical algorithm and historical data, allowed users to forecast the agency spending for the next few years.
- Developed a web application that was oriented to media spending reports, with filters per agency, client, country and media type; used ASP.NET MVC, jQuery, and MDX queries.
- Built a web application for media agencies which allows users to manage the entire workflow of media contracts and billing for a new media campaign; used ASP.NET Web Forms, jQuery, SQL, and NUnit.

Technologies: jQuery, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, ASP.NET MVC

# **LevelUp games, Hong Kong** — Junior Software Engineer

November 2008 - February 2010

- Worked in the marketing team of game development company LevelUp, with a focus on building marketing automation tools for social media and content marketing.
- Eliminated a huge chunk of manual work done by the team after I created a scheduler with a UI that performed routine marketing tasks and simplified social engagement.
- Reduced the cost of IT infrastructure by rethinking software architecture that allowed to support existing operations with just 1/3 of all machines running in the cloud.

Technologies: Backbone.js, Node.js, JavaScript, MySQL, PHP

# **SKILLS**

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffrey-xue-437010213/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffrey-xue-437010213/</a>

Github: https://github.com/hectorstudio